exede.net 2017-06-22

# 

                                      Exede® Subscriber Privacy Policy
ViaSat, Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “ViaSat,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) respect and value your
                                                                                                                      ®
privacy. In this Privacy Policy (“Policy”), we describe the information that we obtain about users of ViaSat’s Exede
                                                                                                     ®
internet service and related products and services (the “Services”) (but not including our WildBlue service, which is
covered by a separate policy), including information you may provide to access our customer portals at
http://exede.net or https://my.exede.net (“Sites”) related to our Services. This Policy does not apply to users of our
other websites such as www.viasat.com, www.exede.com and www.wildblue.com, which are governed by the
Website Privacy Policy available at www.exede.com/legal, or any third party websites that you access through the
use of our Services. By visiting our Sites or using our Services, you agree that any information you provide to ViaSat
will be handled as described in this Policy, which is incorporated by reference into the applicable Customer
Agreement or terms of service.
INFORMATION COLLECTION
ADVERTISEMENTS AND THIRD PARTY ADVERTISING
YOUR CHOICES
HOW WE USE INFORMATION COLLECTED
INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE
DATA SECURITY
LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES
CUSTOMER PROPRIETARY NETWORK INFORMATION
SPECIAL INFORMATION FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS
ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
HOW TO CONTACT US
INFORMATION COLLECTION
           Information You Provide to Us
ViaSat collects personal information from you when you use our Services, create an account with us, request
information from us, or otherwise contact us. The personal information we collect may include your name, address,
email address, phone number, account login credentials (such as a username and password), and a credit or debit
card number or other financial information (“Information”). We may combine the Information you provide to us with
information from and about you that we receive from third parties, including business partners and vendors, or
information that we automatically collect when you visit the Sites.
You may update or change your contact and billing information by calling our customer care number at 1-855-463-
9333 (Exede Residential customers) or 1-855-313-4111 (Exede Business customers) or accessing our customer
portals at http://exede.net or https://my.exede.net.
            Information Automatically Collected
When you use our Sites, we may use cookies, log files, or other similar technologies to conduct analytics of our Sites.
For example, we may automatically collect certain non-personal information from you such as your browser type,
operating system, software version, Internet Protocol (IP) address, Internet service provider and platform types. We
may also collect non-personal information about your use of the Sites, including the areas or pages of the Sites that
you visit, the amount of time you spend using the Sites, the number of times you return to the Sites, the amount of
time it takes to load a page, the order in which the content on a page loads, and other Site usage data. This
information helps us to track and understand how visitors use our Sites, and improve the performance and user
experience of our Sites.
We may also collect information regarding your use of our Services and how our Services perform, including account
login credentials, the amount of time it takes to load a page, the order in which the content on a page loads, your
browser type, IP address or media access control (MAC) address, cookies, domain and subdomain names and the
complete addresses (“URLs”) of the websites you visit. If you connect devices (via a wired and/or wireless
connection) to our modem, we may also collect information specific to each device you connect, including, but not
limited to, the device’s unique MAC address, the hostname of the device, connection properties specific to each
device, the times the device connects to or accesses the modem and the amount of data each device consumes. We
may use the information described in this paragraph to troubleshoot your home network and to optimize,
troubleshoot, measure, and monitor the performance of our network and Services, including performing de-bugging,
measuring service levels and identifying loading trends and websites that are statistically significant to our user
population in order to deliver internet traffic more efficiently.
                                                                1

                                      Exede® Subscriber Privacy Policy
           Information You Post
Any comments or personal information that you post on public pages (such as social media sites), within the Sites or
otherwise, is publicly available and may be viewed, collected, and used by others, including ViaSat. ViaSat is not
responsible for the accuracy of any information contained in those postings. When you post on the Exede Internet
Community forum at community.exede.com, which is hosted by Get Satisfaction, your posts are governed by Get
Satisfaction’s posted privacy policy, and not this Policy. We generally use the information you provide on that site to
respond to customer inquiries or otherwise assist our customers.
           Cookies and Other Tracking
We and our service providers may use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of
our Services and may combine this information with other Information we or our service providers collect from you.
Cookies. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your browser to
enable our systems to recognize your browser. Cookies allow a web server to transfer data to a computer for
recordkeeping and other purposes. We and our third party service providers may use “cookies” on our Sites to
facilitate your ongoing access to and use of the Sites, as well as to conduct analytics on and collect usage data
related to our Sites.
For example, we may use cookies to remember your username and password, if you choose to store them. We may
also use cookies to determine when your current session on the Sites should be logged out after a period of no
activity, as well as for efficient management of the servers providing our Sites.
There are two types of cookies we use on the Sites: session-based cookies and persistent cookies. In addition, we
may also allow vendors to use “third party” cookies for specific purposes on our Sites. A description of each of these
cookies is provided below.
Session Cookies. Session cookies exist only during an online session. They disappear from your computer when you
close your browser or turn off your computer. When you authorize us to do so, we may use session cookies to allow
our systems to uniquely identify you during a session or while you are logged in to the Sites. This allows us to
process your online transactions and requests and verify your identity, after you have logged in, as you move through
our Sites.
Persistent Cookies. Persistent cookies remain on your computer after you have closed your browser or turned off
your computer. When you authorize us to do so, we may use persistent cookies to allow our systems to remember
you and automatically log you in to our Sites.
Third Party Cookies/Applications. We may also engage third party services such as Google Analytics to provide us
with information that helps us improve our Services and the experiences of our customers. These third party services
may use session or persistent cookies or other applications to uniquely identify you via your user credentials while
you are logged in to our Sites. These third party cookies and other applications do not collect any personally
identifiable information other than the user credentials you provide.
Clear Graphics Interchange Formats (“GIFs”). Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function
to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly
on web pages. In addition, we or our service providers may also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our customers to
help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed and track whether our emails are forwarded.
           How We Respond to Do Not Track Signals
While most browsers will allow you to block cookies by enabling a Do Not Track header within the browser, our
system does not recognize Do Not Track headers. However, we only use cookies as described in this Policy.
ADVERTISEMENTS AND THIRD PARTY ADVERTISING
We may offer promotions through our Services. Some of these promotions may be based on your Information or your
use of the Services and others may be based on your Information or your use of the Services combined with other
customer information. We also use third parties such as network advertisers to assist us in displaying our
advertisements on third party websites, and to evaluate the success of our advertising campaigns. Network
advertisers display our advertisements on third party websites based on your use of our Services. This information
                                                            2

                                      Exede® Subscriber Privacy Policy
enables us to target our advertisements to potential new customers. Third party ad network providers, advertisers,
sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs),
Flash LSOs and other technologies to measure the effectiveness of the ads they place for us and to personalize
advertising content. These third party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third party’s specific
privacy policy, not this Policy.
YOUR CHOICES
If, at any time, you would like to stop receiving marketing emails from us, you may follow the opt-out instructions
contained in any such email or make an opt-out request by visiting www.exede.com/opt-out. Please note that it may
take up to 10 business days for us to process marketing email opt-out requests. If you opt-out of receiving marketing
emails from us, we still may send you emails about your account or any Services you have requested or received
from us, or for other customer service purposes. Additionally, you may receive marketing or advertising emails from
ViaSat dealers who act independently of ViaSat. Dealers are independent contractors authorized to sell ViaSat
services in addition to other services. ViaSat does not control marketing or advertising emails from dealers to ViaSat
customers that were developed independently from ViaSat.
You may opt-out of our collection of the complete URLs you visit by calling us at 1-855-463-9333. Please note that it
may take up to 10 business days for us to process complete URL opt-out requests. We will honor such requests not
to collect complete URLs, although we may utilize information about websites that our subscribers visit, in the
aggregate, for purposes of internal network management and service performance optimization.
HOW WE USE INFORMATION COLLECTED
ViaSat may use the Information we collect from and about you for any of the following purposes:
          To fulfill orders, provide Services and communicate with customers;
          To develop new products or services;
          To respond to your inquiries;
          To market our Services to you and engage third parties to help us market our Services;
          To contact you with information, newsletters and promotional materials from ViaSat or on behalf of our
           partners and affiliates;
          To contact you when necessary;
          To troubleshoot your home network and to optimize, troubleshoot, measure and monitor the performance
           of our network and Services, including performing de-bugging, measuring service levels and identifying
           loading trends and websites that are statistically significant to our user population in order to deliver internet
           traffic more efficiently;
          To address problems with the Sites or our business;
          To protect the security or integrity of the Sites and our business;
          As described to you at the point of data collection; and/or
          To use and disclose your credit/debit card information or other financial information only to process
           payments and prevent fraud.
Please also note that in accordance with applicable laws, your Information may be stored and used for the purposes
described in this Policy in the United States or in any other country in which ViaSat or its subsidiaries, affiliates or
service providers conduct operations.
INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE
ViaSat may send your Information to third parties, including under any of the following circumstances:
          We may disclose your Information to third party vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who
           perform functions on our behalf related to the Sites or Services. For example, these providers may help us
           deliver our current Services to new customers or new Services to existing customers.
                                                              3

                                      Exede® Subscriber Privacy Policy
          We may disclose your Information to outside auditors, professional advisors, potential business transition
           partners, and regulators.
          If we are acquired by or merged with another company, or in the event of a consolidation or reorganization
           involving ViaSat, or if all or a portion of our assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a
           bankruptcy proceeding or as part of a similar transaction, we may transfer the Information to the acquiring
           company or other involved third party.
          We may disclose your Information to respond to legal process, such as a subpoena or court order, to
           comply with the law or to protect our rights in litigation or arbitration.
          We may disclose your Information where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action
           regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the safety or property of
           any person or entity (including ViaSat), or violations of our Customer Agreements or policies..
DATA SECURITY
ViaSat has taken certain physical, administrative, and technical steps to safeguard the Information we collect from
and about our customers and visitors to our Sites. While we seek to ensure the integrity and security of our network
and systems, we cannot guarantee the security of the Information, and we encourage you to take precautions to
protect your personal data when you are on the Internet.
You are responsible for maintaining the strict confidentiality of your account password, any Site login or user ID
information, and ViaSat device credentials, and you shall be responsible for any access to or use of the Sites or
Services by you or any person or entity using your password, login or user ID, whether or not such access or use has
been authorized by or on behalf of you.
Our Sites and online applications are for the sole use of ViaSat customers in managing their accounts and the
products and services they receive. If you choose to provide access to certain of your account data to third parties,
ViaSat cannot be held responsible for any release of account or personal data that occurs as a result of the access
that you provide to others.
LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES
At times, our Sites may contain links to third party websites or applications, including third party products or
services. Any access to and use of such linked products or services is not governed by this Policy, but, instead, is
governed by the privacy policies or terms of use of those third parties, even though some of these other products or
services may be co-branded with us. We are not responsible for the information practices of such third parties.
CUSTOMER PROPRIETARY NETWORK INFORMATION
ViaSat collects and maintains certain customer proprietary network information ("CPNI") as part of our Exede Voice
service. CPNI includes, among other things, how you use the Exede Voice service (for example, calling records) and
your billing information. Your Exede Voice telephone number, name, and address do not constitute CPNI. Federal
law generally permits ViaSat to use CPNI in its provision of the Exede Voice service, including billing and collections
for such service. Federal law and regulations permit ViaSat to use, disclose or permit access to CPNI (i) to provide or
market service offerings among the categories of services to which you already subscribe, or (ii) for legal or
regulatory reasons, such as to respond to a court order, to investigate fraud, to protect ViaSat's rights or property or
to protect other users of ViaSat’s services against unlawful, fraudulent or abusive use of ViaSat's services. ViaSat
does not sell or trade your CPNI with anyone outside of ViaSat and those third parties authorized to perform functions
on ViaSat's behalf related to the performance of the Exede Voice service, except as the law may require or permit or
you may otherwise authorize. Neither ViaSat, nor any third party to whom ViaSat has provided CPNI, uses CPNI for
marketing purposes, except as may be permitted by law.
SPECIAL INFORMATION FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS
California residents may request a list of all third parties to which we have disclosed certain Information about you for
the third party’s direct marketing purposes. ViaSat does not currently disclose any Information to third parties for their
direct marketing purposes.
                                                               4

                                  Exede® Subscriber Privacy Policy
ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
If you have an account for our Services, you may sign in to your account and update your personal information
contained in the account.
CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY
ViaSat may amend this Policy from time to time. When we do, we will post the change(s) on the Sites. If we make
any material changes in the way we use or disclose the Information you provide to us, we will provide appropriate
notice to you.
HOW TO CONTACT US
If you have any questions that you would like to ask about this Policy or about our handling of your Information,
please contact customer care at 1-855-463-9333 (Exede Residential customers) or 1-855-313-4111 (Exede Business
customers).
Effective Date: November 15, 2015
                                                       5
